Onur **Altuntaş**

Linkedin altuntasi





Talented Software Engineer has professional experience over three years who graduated from Computer Engineering, Detail oriented and molivated to stay on task, meet timelines and accomplish goals. Strong analytical and arganizational stills within Web Development Industry, Fluent In Java. Go and Javascript/Typescript programming languages used to develop software within Fronted and Bockend. Complex problems solve with analytical and driven mindset, Froud team player focused on achieving project objectives with accuracy,

Work History

2023-12 - 2024-03

Freelance Fullstack Software Engineer

- self-contracted

 Mostly dealing with Golang and Node is backend endpoints.

 Working on database design problems especially for clients who asks scalable and as simple as possible app.

 Touching some frontend problems (React CSR)

 Exercising on Swelfelt (felf-cudding).

 Researching about AI especially implementations on web technologi

2023-01 - 2023-09

Full-stack Software Engineer

- heregy company

 Designed and implemented scalable application programming interfaces.

 Consulted about JMA(Java Virtual Machine), lava web frameworks like spring/Spring about, Open and Java. Scala Go.Javascript/Typescript programming languages.

 Adopted engineering best practices and delivered highest quality scalable solutions.

 Paired with fellow engineers to brainstorm ideas, debug problems and review code.

- review code.

 Gained experience about system architect, how to develop scaled performant application using monolith (vertical scale) and microservice (hotizontal scale) architectures.

 Performed development, debugging, optimization and automation to support implementation of products and applications.

 Gained experience about database technologies such as MySQL PostgreSQL as SQL Cassandra, Redis, MongoDB as NoSQL

 Calined experience about CIPCO (Cloud Integration and Development) like Gillhub Actions. Circle CI and Jenkins

 Gained experience about CIPCO (Cloud Integration and Development) like Gillhub Actions. Circle CI and Jenkins

 Gained experience about CIPCO (Sould Integration sepsecially AWS(Amazon Web Services).

2021-07 - 2022-12

Junior Software Engineer

- Junior Software Engineer

 Herogi Company

 Wacked to improve Herogi that makes automated workflows for fast
 moving austomer data.

 Wacked on how to decide large client side application's software
 architecture, designing backend Api, crealing database queries etc.

 Consulted with engineering team to determine how to develop
 improvement and feature plans.

 Gained experience about agile software engineering principles like standups, planning sessions, spirits and pair programming.

 Used software development tools like Git, Bilbucket, Jira , Slack, Teamotly
 etc.

- etc.
 Worked on monitoring application like Grafana to get alert and fix error.
 Made migration of application in from legacy Angular u to modern React
 of tor designing simple views for each state in application.
 Worked on Redux (brary to manage React state management so that we
 can make easily debug, test and run different environments.

2021-01 - 2021-06 Software Engineering Intern

- Heracy Company

 Collaborated with software engineers to develop and test application procedures for system efficiency.

 Prepared and submitted reports and other documentation to assist development team members.

 Demonstrated time management, organizational, prioritization, and planning skills by successfully handling tasks, projects and priorities.

 Worked on mostly modern web development, Technologies like Ithml. Css and libraries, Javascript, Typescript and functional programming.

2019-02 - 2019-03

IT Software Engineer Intern

- Econology, Essgein:

 Supported Student learning objectives through personalized and small assistance.

 Working with internal and external network devices setup and configuration.

 Achieved destdor app by designing and implementing database connected data formatting app project during internship.

 Lied SAP to achieve paper documents electronically, increasing usability and office organization.

Education

2016-09 - 2021-06

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering

High School Diploma

. Anatolia Teacher High School - Kırşehir Turkey

Lanavaaes

Turkish

Skills

JavaScript / TypeScript

React / React Native

Spring / Spring Boot System Architecture / Scalable Apps Database Management and Technologic

Client presentation

Programming Life Cycles / Agile-Scrum

Flexible and Adaptable
Teamwork and Collaboration

Interpersonal Communication

Active Listenina

Certifications

Udemy - Javascript-advanced

Udemy - Spring-framework5-beginner-to-guru Udemy - Spring Boot Microservices with Spring Cloud Beginner to Guru

Udemy - Sıfırdan React ve Context Api Udemy - Devops Fundementals - CI/CD with AWS+Docker+Jenkins

Udemy - Scala Functional Programming Essentials

Youtube, Stackoverflow and other platforms resource:

Udemy Golana Complete Developer's Guide Self Projects

- Swellekit e-commerce frontend with SSR
 Golong e-commerce monolith backand with Postgres Nosal spring boot manolith to microservice Chall App Full-Stack Spring Boot monolith ballog App Backend
 Spring Boot microservice Slog App Backend
 Spring Boot inforcessive Slog App Backend
 Spring Boot Event Ticket Generator Monolith Backend
 Spring Boot Event Ticket Generator Frontend
 Java Swing Secure Password Stare Generator
 Go Simple Notebook Cil CSV store
 Go-Fiber monolith Blog App Backend
 Firebace Simple Chal App Backend
 Reack-Redux Simple Chal App Backend
 Reack-Redux Simple Chal App Backend
 Seach-Redux Simple Chal App Backend

Accomplishments

Tublitak 2209-A University Students Research Projects Support Program 2020. Our project name Emotion Recognition by Thermal Camera has been supported.